This is going to be quite a chore to find just one book.
She couldn't be...
Who's there?
What do you want, scarred man?
You look like her.
But there's no way you could be...
I smell something, I smell something.
It's the smell of an Ishbalan, covered with blood.
You intend to involve yourself with
the Fullmetal pipsqueak, don't you?
We can't have that.
We still need the boy to pursue the Philosopher's Stone.
What are you talking about?
Oh dear, perhaps I said too much.
Can I eat this one too?
Man cannot obtain anything
without first sacrificing something.
In order to obtain anything,
something of equal value is required.
That is alchemy's
Law of Equivalent Exchange.
At the time, we believed that
to be the true way of the world.
We're here! Central!
Phew! How about we head for the first branch right away?
Brother, hold on!
You don't need to hurry.
The library isn't going to run off!
We've finally got a definite lead!
I can't just sit still now!
Major Armstrong,
we have come to greet you.
Well done.
I will be proceeding directly to the command center,
so you will be in charge of
guarding these two from now on.
Lieutenant Maria Ross!
Sergeant Denny Brosh!
It's an honor to meet you, Fullmetal Alchemist.
Wow, you're dressed just as your second name implies!
You do indeed wear it with dignity.
This happens all the time.
Eh, I'm used to it.
Then it's this little fellow—
N-No, I meant...
I didn't think you were
going to be a child like this...
Aah, enough already!
Major! We don't need any guards!
The two of us are both
perfectly put back together!
I really would like to
let you go as well, but...
We have received information that Scar has appeared again in Central.
That's right.
Just put up with it for now.
Fullmetal Alchemist,
please leave everything to us!
I just hope you don't
slow me down.
Ah, we have a car waiting!
I apologize.
He's always like that.
Please don't let it bother you.
Despite how he appears, he has
overcome a bitter past many times...
Please overlook his behavior for me.
R-Right...
But actually, as it happens...
Last night, the first branch was all but
completely lost due to a fire that broke out.
You're kidding me, right?
According to eyewitness reports,
we suspect that it was the act of Scar,
who is on our wanted list.
Brother...
Our lead is burned to a crisp...
Really! Seriously, seriously! I want you to hear her too!
She's a prodigy!
And she's only three years old!
She has an angelic singing voice!
That settles it!
She's going to be a future songstress!
Lieutenant Colonel, I'm working here.
Huh? Fancy that! I'm working too!
Jeez...
I wonder if there is any alchemy that can burn someone up on the other end of the phone.
You say such frightening things,
Flame Alchemist.
Now then, about that other matter...
According to eyewitness testimony,
we're certain that Scar was involved.
However, looking at the site, I can't
believe it was the work of him alone.
There is evidence that he was fighting with someone.
Any news on Scar?
Signs of fighting continue on away from the building site into the sewers.
We discovered his bloodstained clothes further downstream,
but we're not sure
if he's alive or dead.
Right now in Central, following the death of Brigadier General Grand,
there are plausible rumors going around that Colonel Mustang will be returning.
Then again, there are others that are putting forward the misdirected notion
that you're the one
behind the disturbances.
Hm, how ridiculous. But then...
Returning to Central, huh?
That doesn't sound bad.
Watch yourself. You've got a lot of enemies among the higher-ups right now.
I'm ready for them.
Make as many friends as you can,
who understand you and will support you.
Which means,
as soon as you can...
find yourself a wife!
Shut up!
Colonel, take it easy on the phone.
Lieutenant Colonel! Don't sit up there!
We've been searching
since this morning,
but these are the only books we were able to recover.
This is terrible.
Brother...
Sure enough, there aren't any books
authored by Tim Marcoh in the main building.
If they had been moved there
from the branch,
there should be
a record of it, after all.
Um, is there any possibility that it was checked out by anyone?
Yes, but since the circulation records were also burned up...
I see...
It was probably burned up
together with all the others.
If only we could have confirmed that his book was really even in there...
Was there anyone else
who worked there?
He and I were the only people on staff in that branch.
Just you two?
Only State Alchemists were
permitted in the branch, and all.
I think I remember there being
a young lady there who wore glasses.
Ah, you mean Scieszka?
She was fired a little while back.
Fired?
That girl was a little unusual.
Scieszka was a bookworm.
Worm?
I guess she isn't home.
The lights are on. Let's open it!
You can't!
What a mountain of books!
Does someone actually live here?
Scieszka-san, are you here?
Scieszka-san!
She's not here.
Help! Help!
There's someone...
There's someone buried here!
Dig! Dig! Just keep digging!
Thank you very much.
I inadvertently knocked over
that pile of books.
I couldn't breathe,
and I thought I was going to die.
Scieszka-san, you used to work at the first branch, right?
Yes. All I ever did was read books while I was working, so I got fired.
I have to support my sick mother,
but I'm just no good at anything besides reading books.
Um, anyhow, Scieszka-san,
do you remember there being a book
authored by someone named Tim Marcoh at the branch?
Tim Marcoh?
It would probably be a thick,
handwritten research journal.
A thick, handwritten research journal...
by Tim Marcoh...
Yes, I remember!
It was a leather-bound book,
with handwritten manuscripts inside.
Are you sure about that?
Yes. I remember all of the books in the branch's collection.
Which would mean, sure enough...
Damn. We're right back
where we started.
Brother...
Yes, indeed.
It sure is sad when you can't find a book you want to read.
I know that feeling terribly well.
I, too, once wandered among this mountain of books for nearly three days,
but I still did not find the
one volume I wanted to read.
It's so, so sad...
S-Scieszka-san, thanks.
With your help, we at least
confirmed that the book existed.
We'll manage to do
something from here on.
You mean, there's still
some other way?
I'm going to transmute the cinders of all the burned books back to their original form!
Incredible! Can you really do something like that?
Watch closely!
Uh, what about that?
Is it okay for that stuff
to go flying off?
No matter how hard you try, it'll be impossible, Brother.
Um, if you would like,
shall I reproduce the book for you?
I remember the entire contents of a book once I read it.
And since I've read most of the books in the branch...
You mean it?
Can you really do that?!
It's a silly little talent I have, but if I can help you out...
Here you go!
There was a lot of content,
so it took me three whole days
to write it all down.
This is Marcoh-san's
research journal? Really?
Yes!
Everything from light and easy hors d'oeuvres,
to party dinners you'd invite guests to.
Tim Marcoh's "1,000 Recipes for Today's Menus"!
Right?
One tablespoon of sugar,
a pinch of salt and pepper...
This really is today's menu.
Are you sure you didn't get the wrong author?
You're not serious! All I did was reproduce what I was told to.
It was all in vain, I'm sorry to say.
No...
You're sure that, word for word, this is
the same thing that Marcoh-san wrote?
Yes, no doubt about it.
You're incredible! Thanks!
Lt. Ross!
Give Scieszka this amount of money for me.
If you go to State Alchemist Services with my references there,
they'll take it out of my
research budget for you.
Al, let's go!
Hold on!
Sergeant, here.
What is he planning to do with a book like that?
Indeed...
Th-That much?!
For him to pay out
this amount all at once,
he sure is a State Alchemist!
Wait, please!
Where are you going?
We're going to hole up in the Central Library for a while.
They have abundant materials and dictionaries, after all.
You can't mean it!
Scar's whereabouts are still unknown.
We can't guard you in
such a high-traffic area!
Well, you can report that to your superiors,
or whatever else you like!
This is our problem!
We've finally found ourselves a lead. Sorry.
Marcoh-san's research journal...
It definitely appears to be
an ordinary cookbook at first glance.
The secret to the Philosopher's Stone
is written in here, huh?
It's encoded, to protect
against it being misused.
They do say that alchemy was born in the kitchen, after all!
With me working on this, it'll be a piece of cake!
And here I thought I could solve this right away...
This is one hard code to break.
If only we could ask
Marcoh-san directly.
He abandoned his research.
We can't very well
rely on him anymore.
Yo, Ed, Al!
Are you doing all right?
Lt. Colonel! What's the deal?
We haven't seen you around at all!
It's Scar's appearance.
He's got us running all over.
Al, did you get your body fixed up all right?
Yes, thank goodness.
Those two are on familiar terms with the Lt. Colonel!
Lt. Colonel Hughes!
If anything were to happen here,
we could not ensure the safety of these two.
They should return to quarters at the Command Center.
I asked you to leave us alone!
As long as we do not know
where Scar is,
we should reexamine
our security structure!
Lt. Ross is definitely right.
Lt. Colonel!
However, I can't make the call
on my own authority.
Why don't you ask Major Armstrong?
No! Please, not him!
No, not him!
Lt. Colonel,
I'm just one step away.
I'm begging you.
I'm at a point where I can't do
very much about the Scar matter...
On top of that, all the case records have been burned up.
There isn't any work to be done.
Case records?
Those were at the branch as well?
Uh-huh. Affidavit records,
lists of names, the whole bit.
Lt. Colonel!
Me?!
Um, sure, I've read the military's
criminal records and lists of convicts.
You'll be fine.
If what you say is true,
this will help us out greatly.
I'll vouch for her. If you're going to hire her, now's the time.
You mean it? To think that I,
whose only ability is reading,
would become part of
the Court-Martial Office...
It's not like that.
Working at something really hard is a talent in and of itself.
You have an incredible memory, after all.
I think you should be proud of it.
Thank you.
Um, I will do the best I can!
Thanks for your consideration!
All right! Now that that's settled, let's get right to work.
I pay handsomely!
Thank you very much!
I guess I've got no choice.
I'll send someone from the
Court-Martial Office to cover library security.
Eh? Thanks, man. And I didn't even mean for this to happen, either.
Liar!
See you later. Don't go
working on that too hard.
Just a moment please, Lt. Colonel!
Lt. Ross...
I know what you're going to say,
but they are not the kind of guys
who give up easily.
I'll dispatch additional men to you by tomorrow.
I'm asking you to make do.
Why are you supporting them this much?
Letting them continue to work,
when you know the danger to them...
Those boys are still children!
Which is why we're protecting them.
Right now, what they're doing is something that only they can do.
It is the role of us adults to
watch over children like them.
I leave you to it.
Brother!
You're homunculi, are you?
My, there are still humans
who believe in our existence.
I didn't get to eat him.
I would've liked to have verified Marcoh's research journal.
But now there's no need to, is there?
Ah, you're awake?
This is a surprise. I didn't think
you were going to come back to life.
Where am I?
Mister, you're an Ishbalan, right?
Don't worry!
This is a town of Ishbalans!
Grandpa! He's back to life!
You've held on to your life,
young one.
You're the guy, aren't you?
The one on the wanted list.
Relax.
There's no one here who would sell out one of their own.
I had no idea there were
this many surviving Ishbalans.
It's not just here. There are little villages all over the land,
and everyone is still going strong.
"The entire world is the
bosom of our god, Ishbala."
No results today either, huh?
I don't know what it is that they're studying,
but I wish they would
throw in the towel already.
Those boys won't give up until they've found something.
And it's our job to protect them.
You've gotta be kidding me!
Now I understand... the reason
this is called the devil's research...
the reason Marcoh-san
abandoned his research...
Brother...
It's no wonder!
The material needed for making a Philosopher's Stone...
is live human beings!
Huh? What's the matter?
And here I thought...
I finally thought it was
within our grasp!
You're going?
Thanks for your help.
You could just stay here.
I cannot do that.
I am a person who has
betrayed the way of God.
That arm is amazing.
Yeah.
It's something very precious
given to me by my family.
Fullmetal Alchemist...
Episode 19: "The Truth Behind Truths"
Central 5th Laboratory...
There is a hell there
that we were unaware of.